[{"id": "5fea46efff048f679a45aba6", "question": "What is the layer in the earth's atmosphere at 15-30 km altitude called in scientific terms?", "answer": "Ozone layer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a7f6806f5f79087132fb44", "question": "Mount Elbrus is the highest mountain in which country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b0", "question": "Who wrote the Dark Tower series?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c003", "question": "What does a philatelist collect?", "answer": "Stamps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae4", "question": "What 2001 Rachael Leigh Cook film was based on an old Saturday morning cartoon series?", "answer": "Josie and the Pussycats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a116", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Wings Over America\" in 1976?", "answer": "Paul McCartney and Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8d25ec223966ae8f884f", "question": "Who said this in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"? \"Hope is a dangerous thing. Hope can drive a man insane.\"", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa56f73838c5c8a417f25", "question": "Which insect has the shortest lifespan?", "answer": "Mayfly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596761662b59efe0e9417ea3", "question": "What country music artist was nicknamed \"Chief\" after his maternal grandfather, who was Chief of Police?", "answer": "Eric Church", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec234a8dc25ca9e12ef62f", "question": "By what name is \"Calcium oxide\" more commonly known?", "answer": "Quicklime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe5265c1bf59ab7d2e380f6", "question": "What is the coldest permanently inhabited town on Earth?", "answer": "Oymyakon, Russia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b905", "question": "The delicacy known as fois gras traditionally comes from what part of the duck or goose?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6992620565ad31a57c742", "question": "According to the Bible, what was Paul's name before it was Paul?", "answer": "Saul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8df", "question": "What popular tourist destination is Thailand's largest island?", "answer": "Phuket", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c339", "question": "What is the acronym for Thomas A. Swift's Electric Rifle?", "answer": "Taser", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600784b0bd51d85e222ab65d", "question": "Who said, \"Champagne should be dry, cold, and free\".?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc3", "question": "What is floating wreckage of a ship called?", "answer": "Flotsam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a7", "question": "In what year did the San Francisco 49ers become the first five-time Super Bowl champs?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1f", "question": "From 1964 to 1975, who was the original host of the TV game show \"Jeopardy\"?", "answer": "Art Fleming", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e6", "question": "Which state is closest to Bermuda?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace9", "question": "What Harvard dropout held 535 US patents upon his death in 1991, second only to Thomas Edison?", "answer": "Edwin Land", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7d", "question": "How many points are there on the maple leaf on the Canadian flag?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cef", "question": "Jacob and Wilhelm were the first names of what literary brothers?", "answer": "The Brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75e", "question": "What organ gave us the word \"hysterical\"?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45d", "question": "The island country Grenada is also known as what?", "answer": "Island of Spice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eb034f83302ff91e4649a", "question": "Which record label signed The Beatles in 1962?", "answer": "EMI", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b317", "question": "The Canadian Goods and Services Tax came into effect on what date?", "answer": "January 1, 1991", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f5f2cee580c7f8fd1e5b", "question": "Where did the deadliest airline disaster occur?", "answer": "Tenerife", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb57de5dad637d903c880c", "question": "What is the name of the oldest bridge in Venice, which crosses the city's famous Grand Canal?", "answer": "The Ponte di Rialto, or Rialto Bridge, was built between 1588 and 1591 to span the width of the Grand Canal.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d6d62b42d4a3561a9f08", "question": "The Oshawa Generals is a junior ice hockey team located in what country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3eaf44f0f6af5b06664d", "question": "What is the capital of New Hampshire?", "answer": "Concord", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c75d0775fa611bce67d8", "question": "What is the name of the University of Georgia's mascot?", "answer": "The Georgia Bulldogs have a bulldog as their mascot and his name is \"Uga\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c3", "question": "The world's least salty seawater is found in the Gulf of Bothnia, between what two countries?", "answer": "Sweden and Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf99", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, which two letters have the highest values?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bbd0fb6c85e9e634ff59", "question": "What is the word \"laser\" short for?", "answer": "Light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fdc", "question": "What nationality was musician and composer James Last?", "answer": "German", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a8d790aac110e4167092", "question": "If you order a Snakebite cocktail in the UK, what would you get?", "answer": "A mix of lager and cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabc", "question": "Tarsus and metatarsus are parts of which body part?", "answer": "The foot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab1b3234fda37788a9a1dc0", "question": "What is the basis for guacamole?", "answer": "Avocado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b502fb6c85e9e634ff45", "question": "Where is the \"Land of 10,000 Lakes\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc03c6de0eb824d4052d8", "question": "How did the Pacific Ocean get its name?", "answer": "Portuguese explorer, Ferdinand Magellan named it \"Mar Pacifico\", which means \"peaceful sea\" in both Portuguese and Spanish.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339037", "question": "What is non-rhyming poetry called?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071df63745b36be73039e0", "question": "What is the name of the first Lunar Module to land on the Moon?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b327", "question": "Who was the first African American mayor of Chicago?", "answer": "Harold Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339481", "question": "What was David Dunn's weakness in the movie \"Unbreakable\"?", "answer": "Water", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee2", "question": "Which US boxer was known as \"The Manessa Mauler\"?", "answer": "Jack Dempsey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389cc", "question": "What animal's head is placed on a stick in \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "A pig's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85c", "question": "The scientist Bernard Vonnegut, brother of famed author Kurt Vonnegut, discovered what commercial use for silver iodide?", "answer": "Rainmaking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc5666ce05a3942286f3d", "question": "The book \"I, Robot\" was written by whom?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c615", "question": "What does Fauna refer to?", "answer": "Animal life", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea337dff048f679a45aaee", "question": "What animal name literally means \"pig-fish\"?", "answer": "Porpoise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07c", "question": "What WWII general was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5658333a95c66dc4fe758", "question": "Which number system uses only the symbols 1 and 0?", "answer": "The binary system", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b2", "question": "What color flag is the signal for surrender?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa77173838c5c8a417f38", "question": "What are people who love eating ice called?", "answer": "Pagophagiacs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002418b4be4723ccac22178", "question": "Characters Spiker and Sponge are the antagonists in which Roald Dahl children\u2019s book?", "answer": "\"James and the Giant Peach\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff514e3ff04d658268c92e5", "question": "What actor was one of the most decorated American combat soldiers of World War II?", "answer": "Audie Murphy\u00a0received every military combat award for valor available from the U.S. Army, including the Medal of Honor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b194", "question": "What year did Napoleon become King of Italy?", "answer": "1805", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fedda1c6ce05a3942286d81", "question": "Red described geology as the study of what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red remarked that geology is the study of time and pressure.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1375469bb8041d07a07f", "question": "What did the \"lemon campaign\" advertise in the 60's?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03d", "question": "In 1969, what woman said \"No woman, in my time, will ever be Prime Minister\"?", "answer": "Margaret Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339270", "question": "What is the name of the Alicia Keys backup singer who won season 2 of The Voice?", "answer": "Jermaine Paul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928e", "question": "Which \"South Park\" character gets killed in almost every episode?", "answer": "Kenny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a046", "question": "What is the name of the town where the Sons of Anarchy have their motorcycle club?", "answer": "Charming, California", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c677", "question": "What inventor was known as the \"Wizard of Menlo Park\"?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a14acad1ec93f27df775", "question": "In a Cortado, what is the main purpose of the milk?", "answer": "To reduce the acidity of the coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83f", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the loops of Henle?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd36", "question": "Whose tombstone, in Siler City, North Carolina, bears the inscription \"Aunt Bee\"?", "answer": "Frances Bavier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339061", "question": "Who wrote the epic poem \"Samson Agonistes\"?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339111", "question": "What boxer appeared in the broadway musical \"Buck White\" in 1969?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2122131a458464a93c447", "question": "Which meat dish becomes particularly popular during the Super Bowl?", "answer": "Chicken wings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f1", "question": "What wondrous creation was designed by Sostratus of Cnidus?", "answer": "Lighthouse of Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1b", "question": "The comic books and movie titled \"300\" is based off of which famous battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Thermopylae", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9043401dd7bf43be5e873", "question": "What was the theme of the first Macy's Thanksgiving Parade?", "answer": "Mother Goose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c025", "question": "What is ochophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Riding in vehicles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76894eec85e375820b2a2", "question": "Which two U.S. national parks are located within the Arctic Circle?", "answer": "Gates of the Arctic National Park and Kobuk Valley National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af50", "question": "What happened on September 1, 1939 that led to Britain and France declaring war on Germany?", "answer": "Invasion of Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d4", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Desert Fox\"?", "answer": "Erwin Rommel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4e", "question": "What late 1970's hit contains the following line \"Ooh, you make my motor run, my motor run\"?", "answer": "My Sharona", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6589bae7e414034b5aef3", "question": "Where did yoga originate?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942a", "question": "The 2007 movie \"There Will Be Blood\" is based on which novel by Upton Sinclair?", "answer": "Oil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab0b36baab681b09292166", "question": "Who was the first king of Jerusalem?", "answer": "King Saul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989acb0cb8751d53e7d760c", "question": "Which two twin primes add up to 360?", "answer": "179 and 181", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969d", "question": "Ben Kingsley won an Oscar in 1982 for which movie directed by Richard Attenborough?", "answer": "Gandhi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90d3a052800b05cac20f18", "question": "What planet in our Solar System has the longest day?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3a", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Mrs. Rachel Lynde Is Surprised\"?", "answer": "Anne of Green Gables", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb8b07e83c707845b2135", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc4", "question": "What US first lady helped draft the Universal Declaration of Human Rights?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339339", "question": "What actress played the role of Pamela Barnes Ewing on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Victoria Principal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339021", "question": "Whose autobiography's main title is \"True\"?", "answer": "Martin Kemp", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c9", "question": "Who directed the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Henry Koster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c967", "question": "What is the fear of flying called?", "answer": "Aviatophobia or pteromerhanophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a470", "question": "What is the capital of Mali?", "answer": "Bamako", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d20", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Tin Cup\"?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a35", "question": "What cover song was Van Halen\u2019s first Top 40 hit?", "answer": "You Really Got Me", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f521ff048f679a45aad2", "question": "Nosocomephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Hospitals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a1", "question": "Mike Judge is best known for creating what two popular characters?", "answer": "Beavis & Butt-head", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e7b2b24f84e0b9f9ffbc", "question": "How many states comprise Australia?", "answer": "Six", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b2", "question": "Which movie was Pixar's first feature film?", "answer": "Toy Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04a", "question": "Gene, Louise, Tina, Bob, and Linda are the main characters of which animated sitcom?", "answer": "Bob's Burgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339286", "question": "Who is the only player in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" to be in the house but not have a key?", "answer": "Jodi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab40", "question": "What place is also known as \"land nearest nowhere\"?", "answer": "Cape Three Points", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0e", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Cornelius?", "answer": "Kellogg's Corn Flakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a8", "question": "Defenestration is the act of being thrown out of what?", "answer": "A window", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd6", "question": "Nicosia is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc19", "question": "What company introduced Spam to the market in 1937?", "answer": "Hormel Foods Corporation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339071", "question": "Stephen King's Dark Tower series is about a Gunslinger named what?", "answer": "Roland Deschain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ddd9fe83fe1f2a824b65", "question": "Which Crayola color was named by a five-year-old?", "answer": "Razzmatazz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03c", "question": "How many stars does the New Zealand national flag have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d5", "question": "What US state name ends with three vowels?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a18", "question": "What 2003 reality series starred a construction worker named Evan Marriott?", "answer": "Joe Millionaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbb3d7e83c707845b2149", "question": "Which band recorded an album in the same California house where an infamous mass murder occurred?", "answer": "The Nine Inch Nails recorded most of their 1994 album \"The Downward Spiral\" at the house where the Manson murders occurred", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a73e", "question": "Oneida Lake is located in which US state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c502fbde8045e48466a5", "question": "What is chionophobia?", "answer": "Fear of snow.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a634", "question": "What city is home to the University of Oregon?", "answer": "Eugene", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b146", "question": "In what year was Stanley sent to Africa to search for Livingstone?", "answer": "1871", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e86006d333868d34d747", "question": "Who was the top Australian flying ace in World War I?", "answer": "Robert Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a836", "question": "The Gadsden Purchase involved the lower portions of what are now which two US states?", "answer": "Arizona and New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e99a0ebfabb9c85d8a974", "question": "Whose first wife was actress Jane Wyman?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3e9e838e4e5d4832e6312", "question": "In the \"Book of Judges\", Gideon stations his army on what mountain before attacking the Midianites?", "answer": "Mount Gilead", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b680", "question": "The organization PETA stands for \"People for\" what?", "answer": "Ethical Treatment of Animals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c2", "question": "How many U.S. states are there?", "answer": "Fifty", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b331", "question": "In what year did the Vietnam War begin?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe765feeec85e375820b27b", "question": "Which mountain range is home to the largest U.S. National Park?", "answer": "Saint Elias Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded0c2ea2747c8aff16d2c", "question": "Which country's wine might be labelled \"DOCG\"?", "answer": "Italy's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b661", "question": "In baseball, a \"gopher pitch\" is referred to as what?", "answer": "A pitch hit for a home run", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5afad9cf430e050a5df0d115", "question": "Who were the first people in the world to eat popcorn?", "answer": "The Natives in the Americas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b536", "question": "What does an archer carry his arrows in?", "answer": "A Quiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22f", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1985 film \"Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d8", "question": "What two authors' characters are used to name the moon of Uranus?", "answer": "William Shakespeare and Alexander Pope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ccbb877e98cb97778a2a", "question": "Avarua, the capital of the Cook Islands, is located on which South Pacific atoll?", "answer": "Rarotonga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3cf9e4f032c0db195b491", "question": "In which caste would you most likely find a Hindu priest?", "answer": "Traditionally, priests have come from the Brahmin varna.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3e", "question": "What Green Day hit spent a record sixteen weeks atop the Billboard Modern Rock chart?", "answer": "Boulevard of Broken Dreams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d9", "question": "What name is given to the line running across a snooker table?", "answer": "Balk line", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9f", "question": "In Greek mythology Cronus and Rhea were the parents of who?", "answer": "Zeus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a929", "question": "Where is the Boxing Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Canastota, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aad", "question": "For whom did Robert May write the story of Rudolph the Red-nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "His daughter, Barbara", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea34e2ff048f679a45aafd", "question": "Which is the densest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab3", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Denmark?", "answer": "Mute swan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cdc", "question": "What literary character's parents were murdered in Godric's Hollow?", "answer": "Harry Potter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecce80ec223966ae8f88b0", "question": "Who did not attend the 1977 premiere of \"Star Wars: A New Hope\"?", "answer": "George Lucas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c8dc877e98cb977789ed", "question": "Which US state is home to Olympic National Park?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d0", "question": "What baseball team suffered from the \"Curse of the Bambino\"?", "answer": "Boston Red Sox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339404", "question": "What is the name of Nicole Kidman's character in the 2001 movie \"Moulin Rouge!\"?", "answer": "Satine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca2", "question": "First published in 1988, who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time\"?", "answer": "Stephen Hawking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc2f6facee580c7f8fd1e5d", "question": "What does \"M&Ms\" stand for in the candy with the same name?", "answer": "Mars & Murrie's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b699285e762b54eb9be9423", "question": "What is the technical term for a 20-sided die?", "answer": "Icosahedron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcff", "question": "What American company had a thirty-foot inflatable gorilla atop its Rhode Island offices for decades?", "answer": "Samsonite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c3", "question": "On what island was Napoleon born?", "answer": "Corsica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1cd807bd84c0ea43ad428", "question": "What is the capital of Macedonia?", "answer": "Skopje", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad11", "question": "By what nickname was Simon Bolivar was also known as?", "answer": "The Liberator", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c580fbde8045e48466ae", "question": "When hyenas gather, what are they called?", "answer": "Cackle -- Many people refer to them as a clan of hyenas, which is equally acceptable, but the proper term is cackle.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66c6fa5bfecdd737e0894", "question": "Which sensation can cats not taste?", "answer": "Sweet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c4", "question": "Which word in computing is used to describe half of a byte?", "answer": "Nibble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac4c", "question": "When was Queen Elizabeth II born?", "answer": "April 21, 1926", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c02", "question": "What is actor Jack Nicholson's full birthname?", "answer": "John Joseph Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e13806d333868d34d725", "question": "Which African nation successfully resisted colonialism in the late 19th century?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc43", "question": "What famous tennis player became Novak Djokovic's coach in 2013?", "answer": "Boris Becker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03a", "question": "Where is the Popliteal Fossa located?", "answer": "Back of the knee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ccf7a10b37b32637bdc44bf", "question": "What is it called when the liquid vapor pressure equals to the pressure of the gas above it?", "answer": "Boiling Point", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae94c7574a5ce6b56b824c", "question": "The cobnut is the fruit of what tree?", "answer": "Hazel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ae", "question": "What year marked the start of the construction of the Colosseum?", "answer": "72 AD", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e6", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Bart of Darkness,\" what does Bart break?", "answer": "His leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff3", "question": "What movie star founded the Hole in the Wall summer camps for ill children?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339669", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339588", "question": "Kathleen Turner was the voice of which character in the movie \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\"?", "answer": "Jessica Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a6a190aac110e416707f", "question": "Who created the Lipton tea brand?", "answer": "Thomas Lipton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339515", "question": "Which 1992 western starring Clint Eastwood, Morgan Freeman and Gene Hackman won the Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Unforgiven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971e0fd89261e916c8e09b0", "question": "Which European city is the game \"Assassin's Creed Unity\" set in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd3", "question": "What TV show did \"Melrose Place\" spin off from?", "answer": "Beverly Hills 90210", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea43dfff048f679a45ab8a", "question": "What condition refers to a low oxygen level in the blood?", "answer": "Hypoxia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa5ea6ce05a3942286ec6", "question": "In the film \"Dragnet,\" who played Sgt. Joe Friday?", "answer": "Dan Aykroyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdffe3b668d7dfe168b5bd", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c4", "question": "What were the colors on the original game of Twister?", "answer": "Red, yellow, blue and green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985c", "question": "In the movie \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Calcifer was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c19", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the first plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Water into blood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97f", "question": "What is the official residence of the president of France?", "answer": "Elysee Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf49", "question": "What is the next-to-last event?", "answer": "Penultimate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388dc", "question": "As punishment for not appreciating Apollo's music, King Midas's ears were transformed into the ears of what animal?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c79", "question": "What animal is Indiana Jones afraid of?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76b58eec85e375820b2c1", "question": "Where can you hike the Bay of Fires?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d5", "question": "How many yards are there in a chain?", "answer": "22", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5e846ce05a3942286e35", "question": "What baseball stadium was the movie \"Major League\" filmed in?", "answer": "Milwaukee County Stadium", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd660f8a5bfecdd737e0839", "question": "Where did the tradition of pumpkin carving originate?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339362", "question": "For how many years was the TV show \"Night Court\" on the air?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b4", "question": "Who played the role of Tom in the TV show \"Rich Man, Poor Man\"?", "answer": "Nick Nolte", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bf", "question": "What did Hannibal Lecter say French people taste like?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a277", "question": "When was actress and pin-up model, Betty Grable born?", "answer": "1916", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd9937e83c707845b217b", "question": "What is the name of the woman Mario is attempting to save from the giant ape in the original Donkey Kong?", "answer": "Pauline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989ae8fcb8751d53e7d7616", "question": "What was the first commercially successful method of manufacturing artificial gemstones?", "answer": "The Verneuil Process (also known as flame fusion)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d1193d4fea7fe947a2228c", "question": "Which song from the \"White Album\" was originally titled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000f0ee9a72b906b34e3cfe", "question": "Which part of a cow does chuck meat come from?", "answer": "Shoulder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3b4dc73aa70ea0b70ae7", "question": "What is the primary mountain range in Iran?", "answer": "Zagros Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae26", "question": "Who did Anne Hathaway marry in 1582?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a599", "question": "What old Massachusetts town is nicknamed \"Witch city\"?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed2", "question": "What is the flower that stands for \"a heart ignorant of love\"?", "answer": "White rosebud", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c803", "question": "What trade name comes from combining the French words for velvet and hook?", "answer": "Velcro", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b313", "question": "The Suez Crisis of 1956 was precipitated by Egypt's plans to do what?", "answer": "Nationalize the Suez Canal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f0", "question": "What is the standard of strength of distilled alcoholic liquors called?", "answer": "Proof", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6b2fffb6c85e9e634ff41", "question": "Despite being released at the end of 1998, who had a  #1 hit in 1999 with the song \"Fly Away\"?", "answer": "Lenny Kravitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c153", "question": "A plague is a group of what insect?", "answer": "Locust", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96acf23c87fd04dd15e15", "question": "As of 2020, who was the last person to go directly from Vice President to President of the United States?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ee", "question": "What two pieces are moved in chess's castling maneuver?", "answer": "The king and rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd30", "question": "Where was the first FIFA World Cup held?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029ef1cad1ec93f27df759", "question": "Above 5,000 ft, coffee beans tend to develop a high level of what?", "answer": "Acidity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf7", "question": "How many hits does it take to sink the submarine in the game of \"Battleship\"?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6ab3b20565ad31a57c826", "question": "Who said, \" The first and best victory is to conquer self. To be conquered by self is, of all things, the most shameful and vile\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c33", "question": "Gilbert Stuart is best known for his work in what genre of painting?", "answer": "Portraits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d3", "question": "Who warned against the \"military-industrial complex\" in his famous farewell address?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca14", "question": "What is another name for the eggplant?", "answer": "Aubergine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a2", "question": "Who was the first victim of the electric chair?", "answer": "William Francis Kemmler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b704", "question": "What was Charlie Chaplin's cane made of?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec3", "question": "In what novel is the language Nadsat spoken?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a30", "question": "What athlete's late-night talk show was cancelled after only 8 weeks, in 1998?", "answer": "Magic Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65db11f3c0ead6880d61f", "question": "Where was the treaty signed ending the Russo-Japanese War?", "answer": "Portsmouth, New Hampshire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffe", "question": "In popular culture, what is a \"Tamagotchi\"?", "answer": "Virtual pet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c48efbde8045e484669d", "question": "What is the name for a group of hyenas?", "answer": "A cackle or clan -- Hyenas are best known for the giggling, yipping sounds they make to express frustration and give warnings.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c131877e98cb97778975", "question": "Where is Grant\u2019s Tomb?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a4a012f2a7826b9b8732", "question": "In the movie \"Spaceballs\" what does the bumper sticker say on the back of Lonestar's ship?", "answer": "I love Uranus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002433f4be4723ccac22193", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Russian-American author Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d8", "question": "Who were Bobby Hatfield and Bill Medley better known as?", "answer": "The Righteous Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d04", "question": "What author's books include \"Call of the Wild\" and \"White Fang\"?", "answer": "Jack London", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e966c7ccba3ffe45786ed", "question": "In which country would you find the Tokaj wine region?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e1", "question": "What California region includes Alameda and Contra Costa counties?", "answer": "East Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5f", "question": "Prague is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339040", "question": "Who wrote a book entitled \"The Adventures of Lord Iffy Boatrace\"?", "answer": "Bruce Dickinson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc1e46ce05a3942286f17", "question": "Who originally recorded the song \"Blue Bayou\"?", "answer": "Roy Orbison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e97b06d333868d34d756", "question": "During World War II, what was the purpose of \"Operation Detachment\"?", "answer": "Capture Iwo Jima", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b783", "question": "Cyanide is often said to have the bitter aroma of what?", "answer": "Almonds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ab", "question": "What nation was led by Pompey the Great?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5c816ce05a3942286e21", "question": "Who wrote the songs for \"The Lion King\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e9", "question": "What was the name of the law firm featured in the TV series \"The Practice\"?", "answer": "Robert Donnell and Associates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78a", "question": "What is the only Canadian Province which borders the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "British Columbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b232", "question": "Who, per her dying wish, is buried next to Wild Bill Hickok?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6a", "question": "Who was killed by John Wilkes Booth?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba2", "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Sudan\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b397", "question": "What did American Harland David Sanders give to the world in the 1930s?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32c", "question": "What does DNA stand for?", "answer": "Deoxyribonucleic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ce6800302c3cfae5c79b718", "question": "How many states and territories in Australia?", "answer": "6 states 10 territories", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21f", "question": "When was \"Macho Man\" Randy Savage born?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8b", "question": "Who designed the famous collection of buildings in Oak Park, Illinois?", "answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Apu's last name?", "answer": "Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ceb", "question": "What musical famility's two oldest brothers, Virl and Tom, were born deaf?", "answer": "The Osmonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989b", "question": "Who said the famous line \"Here's looking at you, kid\"?", "answer": "Humphrey Bogart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b212", "question": "Who was assassinated by Dan White?", "answer": "Harvey Milk and George Moscone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc9", "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4a", "question": "At what age did Robert Downey Jr. study ballet in England?", "answer": "10", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6dd", "question": "What is the target area in Olympic fencing?", "answer": "The torso", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f4a5cee580c7f8fd1e59", "question": "What was the name of the commission that investigated the assassination of John F. Kennedy?", "answer": "Warren Commission", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c9250775fa611bce67e8", "question": "What is hummus made from?", "answer": "Chickpeas -- Hummus is Arabic for \"chickpeas.\" It is a Middle Eastern dish common throughout the Mediterranean region and beyond.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6f03a9e54d890926f6cd", "question": "What country is home to the world's most rapidly-constructed skyscraper?", "answer": "China -- Broad Sustainable Building company built a 57-story building called Mini Sky City in 19 days using prefab components.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c790", "question": "What color is the octopus blood?", "answer": "Light blue", "category": "science"}]